fractal-design.com 2019-10-24

# Legal — Fractal Design

This is the part we’re betting you won’t read. Partly because we’d like to think you know how serious we are about GDPR, personal integrity and cyber-security, but mainly because legal texts just aren’t a lot of fun. But transparency is important, and we want you to know what data we collect, why we do so and how we use it.

The tools we feed your data are SendInBlue (e-mail marketing, see segment 3 below) and Google Analytics in order to learn more about how our website is used.

1\. Usage of website & Cookie policy  
2 Newsletter opt-in, list policy and GDPR information

**1\. Usage of website & Cookie Policy**  
This Cookie Policy explains what cookies are and how we use them. You should read this policy to understand what cookies are, how we use them, the types of cookies we use i.e, the information we collect using cookies and how that information is used and how to control the cookie preferences. For further information on how we use, store and keep your personal data secure, see our Privacy Policy.

You can at any time change or withdraw your consent from the Cookie Declaration on our website. Learn more about who we are, how you can contact us and how we process personal data in our Privacy Policy. Your consent applies to the following domains: www.fractal-design.com

**What are cookies ?**  
Cookies are small text files that are used to store small pieces of information. The cookies are stored on your device when the website is loaded on your browser. These cookies help us make the website function properly, make the website more secure, provide better user experience, and understand how the website performs and to analyze what works and where it needs improvement.

**How do we use cookies ?**  
As most of the online services, our website uses cookies first-party and third-party cookies for a number of purposes. The first-party cookies are mostly necessary for the website to function the right way, and they do not collect any of your personally identifiable data.

The third-party cookies used on our websites are used mainly for understanding how the website performs, how you interact with our website, keeping our services secure, providing advertisements that are relevant to you, and all in all providing you with a better and improved user experience and help speed up your future interactions with our website.

**What types of cookies do we use?**  
Essential: Some cookies are essential for you to be able to experience the full functionality of our site. They allow us to maintain user sessions and prevent any security threats. They do not collect or store any personal information.

Statistics: These cookies store information like the number of visitors to the website, the number of unique visitors, which pages of the website have been visited, the source of the visit etc. These data help us understand and analyze how well the website performs and where it needs improvement.

Marketing: Our website displays product suggestions and advertising. These cookies are used to personalize the advertisements that we show to you so that they are meaningful to you. These cookies also help us keep track of the efficiency of these ad campaigns.

The information stored in these cookies may also be used by the third-party ad providers to show you ads on other websites on the browser as well.

Functional: These are the cookies that help certain non-essential functionalities on our website. These functionalities include embedding content like videos or sharing contents on the website on social media platforms.

Preferences: These cookies help us store your settings and browsing preferences like language preferences so that you have a better and efficient experience on future visits to the website.

In addition to this, different browsers provide different methods to block and delete cookies used by websites. You can change the settings of your browser to block/delete the cookies. To find out more out more on how to manage and delete cookies, visit wikipedia.org, www.allaboutcookies.org

**2\. Newsletter & Opt in/out-policy & GDPR information**

**Why and how are you using my data for e-mail lists and marketing?** **  
** We use your data to send you direct marketing related material, such as product and company news, promotions, surveys, press releases and other things we hope you’re interested in.

The main purpose of collecting the data is to optimize your experience and always send you relevant information.

**Do you have any right to gather and use my data?  
**That is entirely up to you – we need your active consent (opt-in) in order to add you to our e-mail/direct marketing program.

**What kind of personal data do I allow you access to when opting in?** **  
**_E-mail address_  
_Needed and used for sending you direct marketing material_

_First & Last name_  
_Needed and used for personalization in the e-mails_

_Country_  
_Needed and used for personalization based on localization, such as localized promotions local news and events._

**Who else has access to this data?** **  
** Your data is stored at our 3rd party e-mail partner (SendInBlue) encrypted databases within the European Union and according to active GDPR-regulations.

Only marketing personel of Fractal Design have access to this database. We never share your data with other 3rd parties without your written consent.

**Can I opt-out, edit my data or make you purge my information at any time?  ** **  
** Yes. You can always contact Fractal Design to remove your consent manually towards e-mail marketing as well as ask for an export, edit or removal of your current personal data. You are also able to use the opt-out functionality (unsubscribe) in the footer in all of our e-mails.

**How long do you save my data?** **  
** We will save your opt-in information (e-mail, name and country) until you actively choose to opt out or remove this data.

We use cookies to improve our site and your experience. By continuing to browse our site you accept our [cookie and privacy policy](https://fractal-design.com/legal-imprint/).

Close
